hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation
playlist so let's look into another
common issue which you might encounter
while working with tosa and especially
around a string manipulation so uh let's
pick up scenario this is the swag Labs
demo website where I have added two
products into the cart okay and these
are two products uh which have got
different prices now the scenario here
is uh I want to calculate uh the total
price for these two products which are
added into the cart okay so I want to
verify that the total price is as per
the expected results and for that I need
to add these two values uh which are in
dollars right and also there are some
decimal points here so uh how can we do
that uh what is the problem here let's
look at
this so for this uh uh first we will go
ahead and we will scan these two
elements from the
application okay for now uh we are not
able to see uh any elements with those
price so so uh we are going to increase
the filtered items here until uh we see
those price elements and these are the
two price elements here and for now
these are both unique so we don't need
to add any additional Properties or we
don't need to change the identification
mechanism right so we are just going to
add this module now uh I'm going to call
this
cart okay and then save
it and let's clck close this so we have
got our module now so let's go to our
test case folder here called string and
then here we will create a new test case
uh we will call this um
calculate total
price okay and then uh we are going to
add our module here uh which is the
cart now the first uh step is to stor
this values into the buffer which is the
price of these items right uh we could
also change the module attributes here
so that we don't actually see the price
here but we will rename it to item one
and item
two right now if I go back to my test
steps uh I can see item one and item two
here um we have to use uh some property
uh which which is the inner text okay
and we'll store it into a buffer so
we'll call this price
one and we will change the action mode
to buffer here same for this so we will
give the inner text and then price
two okay and then we will change it to
buffer so now we have buffered both the
prices now we need to calculate the
total which is uh we need to sum these
two different price items right now um
if I go ahead and use another test step
here called set
buffer and uh we are going to name this
buffer as the sum right and here we need
to calculate the sum here so we can use
an expression called Cals which
basically can calculate any uh
particular mathematical operation
right um inside this we will use the
buffers um so we have got two buffers
here price
one and price
two so this is the calculation um
expression where we can add two
different prices here so until this uh
it looks fine but will it give the
expected result so let's see that uh
first uh let's go ahead and execute this
before that I will just rename this to
add uh
prices okay and then uh let's go ahead
and run this
okay so now if I look at the scratchbook
here uh you can see uh in the first step
uh it passed so it was able to capture
the price and store it into a buffer you
can see uh this was the first price and
this was the second price but uh when we
try to add these two prices uh you will
see that it will throw an error uh for
the expression so it will see that it is
not a valid expression uh which can be
used in this particular uh caly
expression right so uh this doesn't work
so we cannot directly add these two
prices which contains a dollar
sign now uh what can we do here right so
let's uh make some changes okay so um
let's go ahead and remove this step and
here let's make some changes to the
price one and price two buffer right uh
which has got that particular price
value with the dollar so here uh first
we need to remove that dollar from those
price items okay and how we can do that
is by using the string replace method so
in this string replace uh first of all I
need to pass uh the text which we want
to replace right so that is our buffer
so I'm going to use that b price one
here
and then we need to pass the expression
right so what do we need to replace and
that is the dollar sign here right so we
will mention the dollar here and then
what we want to do with this so either
we can um put a zero uh before the price
or uh we can just uh leave it empty
right so we'll uh replace it with a
white space now uh so this is the
expression so this is the text which we
want to replace then what we want to
replace and then with what we want to
replace right so these are the three
things which uh we need to mention
here and then um I'm going to close this
but there is still a problem here right
do you think this will work uh so how we
can check that is we can right click on
this expression and we can do a
translate
value and you will see that it was not
able to replace place that dollar sign
it was not able to remove that dollar
sign okay now whenever you are using
some kind of special characters you
always need to escape these characters
otherwise it will not work in tosa so
what we need to do here is we need to
replace uh this special character by
adding a back slash okay so let's put it
inside the double codes and then let's
add a back slash here and then the
dollar sign so what this will do is it
will escape this particular character
okay now if I go ahead and translate the
value again this time around you will
see that it has removed or replaced that
dollar uh with a white space so that's
no mod there in this particular value
okay so uh this way we can uh do a
replace uh using the string replace
expression and the same we can do for
the price
two so I will just use this expression
here and I will replace it with price
two that should give me uh the new price
if I just check this again so this is
the okay now uh what we can do is uh now
we can calculate the total here and we
can use the same expression which we
used earlier which is Cals which is the
Cal function and and inside this uh we
are going to use the buffer uh which has
got now the new values right so we are
going to use V price
one and then
plus b price
two okay so now uh let's go ahead and
try this again and let's see if we can
get that total price so let's try and
run
this okay so you can see the execution
has passed this time and if we go ahead
and look at the
logs so the price was Set uh and then uh
it calculated a total price which was
39.9 right now uh if you have got this
total price somewhere on the application
or uh in your requirements you can put
uh verify action mode and verify this
total price as well right so this way
you can use the buffer action mode to
buffer different values from your
application and then you can use the
different string Methods like the string
replace uh to replace some of um the
special characters or some characters
which you want to remove from the values
before you perform some
calculations um and also do some
verifications on them right so this is
very helpful um and it's a very common
scenario you can come across not only uh
for calculating the total price in a
shopping cart but it could be a scenario
in several other situations uh related
to your web
applications that's all for this
particular video if you have any
questions then please leave it in the
comments if you like this video then
please subscribe to our Channel thanks
for watching and I will see you in the
next video